CSCB58 Project File: Winter 2018

Team Member A
-------------
First Name:  Joshua
Last Name: Chong
Student Number: 1001701296
UofT E-mail Address: joshua.chong@mail.utoronto.ca


Team Member B
-------------
First Name: Jason
Last Name: Yuan
Student Number: 1003411426
UofT E-mail Address: jasonnn.yuan@mail.utoronto.ca

Project Details
---------------
Project Title: 
Altera Reflex Hero

Project Description:
Reflex game where player press or switch the correct input at the right timing according to the display on the monitor.

Video URL:
https://youtu.be/VoIBlkBr23Y

Code URL:
https://github.com/huifung96/CSCB58/blob/master/project.v

Proposal
--------
What do you plan to have completed by the end of the first lab session?:
1. Score and lives able to be displayed on the HEX and LED.
2. simple square displays on the monitor along with increasing score.
3. implement a ratedivider such that there can be a small delay for the input

What do you plan to have completed by the end of the second lab session?:
implement the input for playing the game:
linking the input with the timing of the square displayed, which also triggers the score when the input is on time.

What do you plan to have completed by the end of the third lab session?:
1. implement music.
2. debug the whole game.
2. If the main code for the game is completed and debugged, and we have time, implement split screen for 2-player mode.

What is your backup plan if things don't work out as planned?
The game will become more simple and easy.
1. Sound track will not be implemented with the game, which mean the game becomes a reflex game.
2. Only have 1 squre appear in a slower pase and have longer response period for pressing/picking the correct input.

What hardware will you need beyond the DE2 board?
VGA Monitor
Computer

Motivations
-----------
How does this project relate to the material covered in CSCB58?:
FSM will be used to control sequences of squares appearing on the display.
Rate divider for controllnig the clock speed.
Counters for managing the score system.

Why is this project interesting/cool (for CSCB58 students, and for non CSCB58 students?):
This project is cool for CSCB58 students and non CSCB58 students because it is a game. Most people enjoy playing games and understanding how the game works also increase the knowledge of the material covered in this course and how it can relate to gaming field or other industries.

Why did you personally choose this project?:
As gamers, we want to somehow relate what we learn in class to the hobbies we do, which is why we decided to choose this project of creating a game with the knowledge we gained in this course.

Attributions
------------
All codes and resources are original.

Updates
-------
Week 1: 
We were able to run the fsm to display the vertical timing line for our game. We haven't animate the moving note yet, but we are able to display it on each line, we need to animate by next week. (it can be done by adding an extra state to remove the previous drawn pixel, then move onto the next draw state)

We also saw other groups successfully added audio feature in their project, so we will highly consider implementing the music component of the game.

Week2:
We are able to display the timing line pixel by pixel moving along the x axis. 

We are also able to alternate the colour after the bar intersect with the Y axis timing bar, and increase/decrease depend on the user pressing the correct botton or not. The score system is a bit buggy but will be fixed by next section.

The speed of the lines are controlled by user input at the moment, but we will implement auto speed change during next update of the project.(can be done by setting the input inside the module and increment the input after reach the end of the x axis.)

We might keep the line version of the bar instead of only displaying one pixel due to visibility.

If we have sufficent time we will implement the music, but will we keep this game as a reflex time based game for now.

Week 3:
We were able to making LEDs light up to display the number of lives. The lives start at 10 (10 LEDs) and as life is lost the left most LED turns off and the game ends once all lives are lost. A life is lost when the player hits the wrong colour or is too late.

We were also able to make the game alternate colours in such a way that there are no patterns to make the game more difficult. Each time the moving pixel passes the vertical line, it will change colour or stay the same. This differs to what we implemented in Week 2 as that was in a fixed pattern.

We were also able to make the game speed up/down automatically instead of using the SWITCHES. The way it works is, as the game gets longer, it gets faster.

We were unable to animate the pixel so for now we are leaving it such that its a solid bar the moves across the screen which also helps the ability to track the pixel.

We also were able to add more places (vertical bars) to gain points however the vertical bar doesn't display properly which is something we hope to fix before the presentation however points can still be gained as if the bar is there.

We added a Start button so that the user can play the game whenever they are ready.

We also fixed a bug were if you have 0 points and lose another point you will end up with over 90 points.

Final Week:
The game is now 2 players but can also be 1 player if toggle the switch at the beginning of the game to switch the mode. The music is not implemented, because we think that music will be actually not necessary for the actual game play.

Speed of each level is fixed such that it is playable and smooth.

Debugged everything, the game is running perfectly and will run and perform as we wanted it to be. 

The game is completed.

